We're almost there.
(紅蓮)じきに着く。
Are you ready, Yuukimaru?
(カブト)準備は いいか？ 幽鬼丸。
Do I really have to do this?
(幽鬼丸)どうしても
やらなきゃダメなのかな…。
それが お前の役割だ。
That is your duty.
But I know it's going to make me
feel awful again...
でも きっとまた苦しくなる。
If you like, I can tell Yuukimaru for you...
((なんなら ボクから幽鬼丸に
教えてあげてもいいんだけどね。
That the kind, gentle Guren-san whom
he believes is the one he should return to,
唯一 帰る場所だと信じていた
優しい紅蓮さんは➡
is the evil villain who killed his mother...
自分の母親を殺した
極悪人だったってね。
Stop!
やめろ！
なら ボクの命令に➡
Then, carry out my orders.
(素直に従うんだね))
We're running out of time. Let's hurry.
時間がない。 急ぐぞ！
How is it?
(カカシ)どうだ？
(サイ)まだ反応がありません。
There's been no reaction.
そうか…。
I see...
さっきの戦いで➡
She used up considerable Chakra
during that last encounter.
ヤツは 相当のチャクラを
消費しているはずだ。
((ぐっ！))
This is the time to strike.
叩くなら今だ。
ヤツに余計な時間を与えたくない。
I don't want to give her too much time.
I agree. I'm going to widen
the scope of my search.
そうですね。 捜索範囲を広げます。
Damn! Where'd that
Crystal Style user disappear to?!
(ナルト)クソッ！ 晶遁使いのヤツ
どこに消えやがったんだ!?
Don't panic.
(シノ)焦りは禁物だ。
I know...
わかってる。
But if we let her slip away,
Yuukimaru will...
でも アイツを逃がせば幽鬼丸は…。
絶対に見つけてやる！
I'll find him no matter what...!
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
the "impulses" that makes you want to meet it
aitaku naru no shoudou
the "innocence" that makes you want to cry
nakitaku naru no junjou
they've gone into the summer fire
natsu no hi ni tobikonda
the fireflies aren't coming back
hotaru wa kaeranai
you didn't say a single word and left a kiss for me behind
anata wa nanimo iwazu kuchizuke wo nokoshite
and nodded as you still got burned
kitsuzuku mama unazuita ne
it was so sad that my life was wavering
kanashii hodo inochi yurameiteita
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
sha la la my sweet lovely dear
sha la la itoshiki hito
I can also see you right now
anata mo mieteiru no
the dazzling moon will softly
mabayui tsuki ga sotto
illuminate the morning day
ashita wo terashite
and strongly and strongly shine on
tsuyoku tsuyoku kagayaite
The Battle Over
the Barrier
(鬼霧)あぁ…。
(濡羅吏)
もう なんてざまよ 最悪。
Cripes, what's going on...?
This is the pits.
You guys are on the verge of death.
アンタたち
今にも死にそうじゃない。
(鬼鳳)
ケッ お互いさまだろうがよ。
Hah! Speak for yourself.
なんか 意識が遠くなってきた。
Oh... I feel like I'm gonna faint...
こんなところで
くたばってたまるかよ。
As if I'm gonna die in a place like this!
オレらは あのアジトでさえ
生き延びたんだ。
Not after we survived
that hellhole of a camp.
(紅蓮)あれが
三尾を捕らえる封印か。
That's the seal to capture the Three-Tails.
まずいな
かなり作業が進行している。
This is bad. They're well into the ritual.
さあ 幽鬼丸。
Now then, Yuukimaru...
時間がないってのに。
We don't have time...!
おい 紅蓮 ソイツをどうにかしろ。
(幽鬼丸)紅蓮さん。
Hey Guren, do something.
Guren-sann...
もういい。
Never mind!
お前 裏切るのか？
You... Are going to betray us?
アンタに逆らう気はない。
I have no intention of defying you.
でも あの術は
ダメージがでかすぎる。
But that Jutsu will
cause too much damage.
だから頼む もう一度だけ
私にやらせてくれ。
So please...
Let me try one more time.
この期に及んで またそれか。
Not that again?
At a time like this?
そうやって
幽鬼丸を出し渋った挙句➡
In your reluctance to use Yuukimaru,
you've lost almost all your men.
お前は ほんとの手駒を失い
自分自身でさえ ボロボロのありさま。
On top of that,
you yourself have been beaten...
そんな状態で
まともに戦えるとでも？
And you still think you can fight?
それは…。
That's...
今のお前にできるのは
せいぜい…。
The least you can do in that state is...
そうだな 幽鬼丸を使わない方法も
あるにはあるか。
Well... There is a way without
using Yuukimaru.
ただし ことは一刻を争う。
But time is of the essence.
お前が ボクの作戦に
全面的にのるのが条件だ。
This is on the condition that
you follow my orders completely.
わかった。
I understand.
少しでも
おかしな素振りを見せたり➡
The minute you show signs of defiance,
失敗したときは
遠慮なく彼を使わせてもらうよ。
or if you fail, I won't hesitate to use him.
ああ。
Yeah...
フン そういうことさ。
Humph, all right then.
来い 幽鬼丸。
Come, Yuukimaru.
安心しろ
巻き込まれないところまで➡
Don't worry.
I'm taking him where he'll be safe.
連れて行くだけだ。
それで 作戦は？
And what's the plan?
鱗児に作戦は伝えておく
お前は その指示に従え。
I'll tell Rinji the plan.
You just follow his instructions.
(カブト)ここなら
三尾の力も届かないだろう。
The Three-Tail's power
won't reach you here.
紅蓮さん 大丈夫なのかな。
Will Guren be okay...?
自分から言い出したんだ。
She's the one who insisted on this.
命に代えてもやってもらうさ。
She'll have to do it even if it kills her.
この場を動くなよ。
Do not move from this spot.
作戦を聞こうか。
Tell me the plan.
(鱗児)紅蓮さん。
Guren-san...
さっさとしろ 時間が惜しい。
Hurry it up. You're wasting time.
はい カブトさんの情報によれば
封印を警護している２人は➡
Yes. According to Kabuto-kun,
there are two guarding the seal;
暗器使いと 体術使い。
one is a Weapons user
and the other a Taijutsu user.
一度 不意打ちをくらっているので
警戒を強めているはずだと。
They've already gone through
a surprise attack,
so they've increased their guard.
なるほどな。 つまり ヤツらの目を
ひきつける ハデな陽動役。
I see.
In other words, the way to catch
their attention is a flashy diversion.
囮が必要ってわけか。 フッ。
A decoy is necessary.
わかった その作戦でいこう。
All right. Let's do it.
手前の２人は 引き受ける。
I'll take care of those two in front.
でも いいんですかい？ 紅蓮さん。
But are you sure about this, Guren-san...?
囮なら 残りのチャクラでも
やりようはあるさ。
I have enough Chakra to be a decoy.
お前は 隙をうかがい
封印を破ることに集中しろ。
You focus on finding
the right moment to break the seal.
(サクラ)封印内に
三尾が完全に入りました。
The Three-Tails is completely
ensnared within the seal.
(シズネ)よし では このまま
結界四方封陣の範囲を狭め➡
Good. Now let's narrow the sphere
of the Four-Corner Sealing Barrier
三尾の自由を完全に奪う。
(３人)はい！
until the Three-Tails' freedom
is totally restricted!
(リー)あっ テンテン！
(テンテン)わかってる。
- Yes!
- Huh?! Tenten!
- I know!
何者です!?
Who's there?!
大事な封印を守るのが
ガキ２匹とは 笑わせるね。
Two kids protecting the precious seal?
What a laugh.
その術
まさか 晶遁使いですか!?
That Jutsu...!
Are you the Crystal Style user?!
対 晶遁班が 迎えうったんじゃ…。
Isn't the Crystal Style Counter team
supposed to deal with her?!
どうする？
ケツまくって逃げるかい？
So what'll you do?
Run away with your tails
between your legs?
とんでもない！
噂の晶遁使いとの手合わせ➡
No such thing!
I'd like nothing better than to battle
望むところです！
いきがるじゃないか。
the Crystal Style user
everyone's been talking about!
That's some confidence...
for a kid from the Hidden Leaf!
木ノ葉のガキがさ。
みんな 集中して！
Concentrate, everyone!
網は 十分に狭まった。
The net is tight enough!
これより 四方より錠をかけ➡
Now we'll lock it from all four sides
and completely seal the Three-Tails!
三尾を完全に封印する。
(３人)はい！
結界四方封陣 施錠！
- Right!
Four-Corner Sealing Barrier... Lock!
ボクが相手です！
I'm your opponent!
でいや！
うわ！
手応えが妙です これは まるで…。
This resistance is strange...
It's as though...
残念だったね。
Too bad.
結晶で 体を覆って…。
She covered her body with crystal...?
《ったく こんな相手。
Damn...
いつもなら
とっくに終わってるってのに》
Normally, I'd have beaten enemies
like them long ago.
まだまだ！
Not yet!
《残りのチャクラからいって
私が使える術は➡
Judging from the Chakra I have left,
there's just one or two more Jutsu
I can use.
あと１つか ２つがせいぜい。
ならば…》
If that's the case!
《次で決める！》
I'll end it with this next one!
(いの)ああ！
いの！
Ino!
《コントロールが…》
My control...
《クッ 失敗か》
Did we fail?
すみません！
まだ 網は破られていない！
I'm sorry!
The net isn't broken yet! Synchronize!
呼吸を合わせ もう一度
封印の錠をかけ直すのよ！
We'll lock the seal once more!
くたばれ！
Die!
今です！
Now!
(２人)うわ～！
まずい！
しまった！
- This is bad!
- Shoot!
くらえ!!
コラボ忍法 ガマ鉄砲！
Eat this!
Collaboration Ninjutsu!
Wind Style: Toad Water Pistol!
うう！
なに!?
What?!
ナルト君！
(ガマ竜)わ～い うまくいったよ！
Naruto...!
Yay, we did it!
(ガマ吉)このくらい
できて当然じゃ！
That's the way it should be!
やっと見つけたぜ 晶遁使い。
I finally found you, Crystal Style user!
キサマ！
Why you--!
《なんとしても
あの封印だけは…》
Whatever it takes...
that seal must be broken!
シノ。
Shino!
な なに!?
あ！
Wh-What?!
封印が！
(サクラたち)キャー！
The seal!
(ヤマト)先輩！
ん？
Senpai.
Hmm?
ヤマトか。
It's you, Yamato.
(ヤマト)先輩の読みどおり 我々は
敵の陽動部隊と接触しました。
As you predicted, Senpai, we encountered
the enemy's diversionary team.
しかし 敵の戦力はたいした
脅威ではなく 戦闘は終了。
But they weren't very strong and ran off.
その後 隊を２つにわけ
封印班の 警護には➡
Then we split up into two...
リーとテンテンを向かわせました。
I sent Lee and Tenten
to protect the Sealing team.
そちらは？
まずいぞ。 晶遁を破る方法は
見つけたもののヤツに逃げられた。
How about you?
It's bad.
We found a way to counter
the Crystal Style,
えっ！
お前たちは すぐに➡
but she gave us the slip.
What?!
封印班の援護に向かってくれ。
Quickly, go help protect
the Sealing team.
しまった！
Damn it!
《これでは結界が保てない》
We won't be able to sustain the barrier!
(ヒナタ)なんて大きいの？
何これ？
I-It's so huge...!
Wha--?! What is this?!
(みんな)キャーッ！
いけない！
Oh no!
うわ～っ！
なんてチャクラだ。 これが三尾。
What Chakra! This is the Three-Tails...!
結界が破られた。
The barrier is broken!
(トビ)うっひゃ～ 先輩！
Senpai!
ノルマが出ましたよ～！
Our assignment... is here!
グオーッ!!
うぅっ…！
兄ちゃん 怖いよ！
Nii-chan... I'm scared!
なんちゅう衝撃波じゃ！
That shock wave...!
オメエ！ また厄介なところに
ワシらを呼び出しおって！
What kind of dangerous place did
you summon us to this time?!
んなこと言ってる場合じゃ
ねえってばよ！
This isn't the time to talk like that!
目的は果たした。
これでお前らに➡
Our goal has been achieved.
三尾を封印する術は
なくなったわけだ。
You've lost the Jutsu
to seal the Three-Tails.
テメエ 許さねえ！
Why you... I can't forgive you!
フンッ。 鱗児 退くぞ！
Rinji, pull back!
逃がさん！
You won't get away!
うおぉ～!!
うお～！
うわ～！
ダメじゃ～！
No!
うっ… うわっ!!
あっ！
うぅっ！
紅蓮さん… あっ！
Guren-san...
はぁ… はっ！
ヒッ！ ぐ 紅蓮さん！
G-Guren-san!
(幽鬼丸)逃げて！
Get away!
うっ うぅ…。
アイツらは!?
あそこだ。
Where'd they go...?
There...
ダメだ…。
No!
ダメだ！ やめて…。
No...!
イヤだ!!
Stop...!
Don't!
イヤだ～!!
No...!
(大蛇丸)カブトめ…
幽鬼丸の力を引き出そうと➡
Kabuto... You seem to be
having a hard time
ずいぶん焦っているようね。
drawing out Yuukimaru's power.
でも 強制された先になど
本当の力は ありはしない。
If you try to force it out,
it won't be real power.
心から何かを欲し
強く願ったとき➡
When there is true desire in the heart
and that desire is strong...
初めて 己ですら知りえぬ
本当の力を出すことができるのよ。
that is when he finds real strength
that even he did not know he had!
これは…。
Is this...?
What is that...?
I've seen it before...
It's just like back then...
Yuukimaru!
Huh?!
before the reality of a deep breath
sonzai to shinkokyuu no genjitsu wo mae ni
my gaze my very existence tries to challenge it
idomou to suru shisen wa
mistakes are made and in the confusion of it all everything burns into my mind
machigai mo tomadoi mo zenbu yaki tsukeru
in a series of moments
isshun no renzoku no naka de
beyond a great number of promises
ikutsu mono yakusoku no sono ue ni tatte wa
are the words that spilled over from the day as I reflect upon them
kamishimeru ano hi koboreochita kotoba
it's as though I made a vow which expresses these feelings into words
komerareta omoi wa chikai no you de
then it would link the befinning with the present day
kuchi ni sureba ima to hajimari wo tsunagu
it's not in my dreams
yume de wa nakute
that place doesn't exist in a fantasy world either
esoragoto no sekai de mo nai basho de sa
before the reality of a deep breath
sonzai to shinkokyuu no genjitsu no mae ni
my gaze my very existence tries to challenge it
idomou to suru shisen wa
mistakes are made and in the confusion of it all everything burns into my mind
machigai mo tomadoi mo zenbu yaki tsukete
embracing the long path ahead
sono zutto saki wo toraeru
in a series of moments
isshun no renzoku no naka de
Next Episode
Guren-san, did you finish
your moving reunion?
何だ？ あれは…。
Rinji, it's you.
オレ 見たことがある。
I blocked the Hidden Leaf's Sealing Jutsu.
Now let's go back with Yuukimaru.
あれは あのときと同じ…。
It was you, all along.
Huh? What are you talking about--?!
Well, let's get along for
Orochimaru-sama's sake.
You... Why?!
Since you're the trigger to
move Yuukimaru,
who's the tool to control the monster...
Next time: "Red Camellia"
Red Camellia
Let's see, today's mini-corner is... Huh?
あっ… 幽鬼丸！
え～と 今日のミニコーナーは と…。
It's terrible, Naruto-kun!
- It's terrible! Naruto!
大変ですよ ナルト君!!
(２人)大変よ ナルト！
About today's mini-corner...
今日のミニコーナーなんですが…。
ああ そんなら ここに台本が…。
Oh, I have the script right here.
- You won't believe this!
- The script is blank!
それが ありえないのよ！
Huh?!
台本が 真っ白なの！
え～っ!?
Our staff is slacking off.
They left the studio!
スタッフが 手 抜いてんのよ！
(テンテン)現場放棄よね。
Date! Come on out!
A cue card... What?
Ad lib this part?
伊達！ 出てこいや!!
カンペが… なになに？
アドリブでつなげって。
I'm tired from the main episode!
こっちは 本編で疲れてんだよ…。
ならば！
Well then!
I shall perform a one-man act
to show off my beautiful body...
このボクの ワンマンショーで！
ボクの美しい肉体…。
That won't bring in high viewer ratings!
(いの)そんなんじゃ
数字 取れないわよ！
I'll use my feminine wiles
to snare the boys...
私の色香で
男子たちを釘付けに…。
Instead!
How about my weapon collection...
そんなのより私の武器コレクションを…。
This calls for the main character,
that's me! And I'll...
いや ここは やっぱ
主役のオレが バシッと決めてだな…。
There's something weird
about the movement!
いや… なんか
動きが… 変だってばよ…。
Hey! I thought I made it in time...
ちょっと！
間に合ったと思ったら…。
What... I can't... move...
Oh no... It stopped!
(いの)やだ！ 止まっちゃった。
(サクラ)い… 色まで…。
Even the color...
Hey Datecchi! Cut it out! Huh?!
おい こら！ 伊達っち!!
いい加減にしろ！ あ～っ…。
Do you want me to draw this in?
Director?
なんなら ボクが
描きましょうか？ 監督。